In Estonia, a nuclear strike on Moscow has a
в Эстонии ядерный удар по Москве
negative attitude. Because it seems to be
негативно относится Потому что вроде как
Near here Yes, but strikes with
Рядом тут Да Во но удары баллистическими
Tomahawk ballistic missiles, everyone unanimously
ракетами Томагавка все вот единогласно
believes that it is possible,
считают что можно так
so in short, they are screwing you up against
что короче вас там накручивают против
Russia in general harshly. Yes, yes, I’m helping to
России вообще жёстко Да да я я помогаю
screw it up because, well, we see that
накручивать потому что ну мы видим что
Russia  attacked Ukraine and we understand
Россия напала на Украину и мы понимаем
that we can also be attacked, so we
что и на нас также может напасть поэтому
must strike
надо бить
first Hello,
первым Здравствуйте
dear, you are
добрый Вы
from Russia, I see Russia, I am Estonia,
откуда Россия я вижу Россия я Эстония
the city of Tallinn, you  what city in
город Таллин Вы из какого города
Russia is this from near Moscow, a small
России это рядом с Москвой небольшой
town, maybe you don’t know the first two
город может быть и не знае первые две
letters Tell Pavlovsky Pasad the first
буквы Скажите Павловский Пасад первые
two letters said understood and the World Cup Are you communicating
две буквы сказал понял а ЧМ Общаетесь
No, I didn’t know, I’m just
Нет не знал просто
sitting in your refrigerator, I’m looking at it so much for Diza it’s
сижу у вас холодильник смот так за Диза
interesting
интересно
There’s a bunch of magnets here You
Тут куча магнитов Это вы
hung that Well,  I have two children, it’s them. And I
навешали Ну у меня двое детей это они А
just realized that my eyes are getting lost
понял просто у меня аж глаза теряются
there, everything is so short, everything is painted,
там всё короче такое разрисованы всё
some jars are placed, it hurts right in my
расставлено какие-то баночки он прямо в
eyes from these too, yes, I  I just love
глазах ребит от этих тоже да ви Я люблю
minimalism
минимализм
And I understood from the flag that you have the flag of
просто А я по флагу понял у тебя флаг
Estonia, I understood that you understood Well, you have the
Эстонии я понял что ты понял Ну у тебя
Estonian flag behind your back now. Well, I
флаг Эстонии сейчас за спино Так я же
told you that I am from Estonia And you yourself are
тебе сказал что я из Эстонии А ты сам
Russian,
русский
no Estonian.
нет эстонец
Damn, your Russian is cool. Well, we have
Да блин У тебя классный русский Ну у нас
everything  I was not born I was born in eighty-
все я родился не Я родился в восемьдесят
one That is, I lived for another 10 years under the
первом году То есть я ещё 10 лет при
USSR
СССР
I lived in eighty-three for 2 years I’m
жил я восемьдесят третьем на 2 года мне
left with how I feel about
оста как я отношусь к
Russians Well, let’s say it’s not the same for those who live in
русским Ну допустим к тем кто живёт в
Estonia  those who live in Yes, there are two categories for those who
Эстонии не тем кто живёт в Да к тем кто
live in Estonia:
живёт в Эстонии отношусь есть две
those who support Estonia
категории те кто поддерживают Эстонию
normally. They are our citizens and
нормально Они наши граждане да те
those who say the
которые вата которые говорят вот там
Soviet Union is there, Russia is there, and so on. Yes, I am for
советски Союз там Россия и так дальше Да
their deportation to their
я за ихнюю депортацию на ихнюю
historical
историческую
homeland, and which ones are more in general?  there are more
Родину а каких больше вообще больше
Estonians in Estonia Well, from some of the
эстонцев в Эстонии Ну вот из части
Russians, what is the percentage of those who are
русских сколько это процент таких кто
right? Well, as you say in Aty, well,
прямо Ну как ты говоришь в Аты ну
look, here in Latvia it’s worse And
смотрите У нас вот в Латвии похуже А у
here in Aty somewhere  5% of the population in
нас в Аты где-то 5% населения в
Estonia is insignificant, but no matter how they make a
Эстонии несущественно но как бы
political movement, they don’t do
политическое движение они не делают
anything serious, but
какого-то серьёзного но
rar them as potential agents of the
рари их как потенциальную агентуру
Russian Federation in the war against
Российской Федерации в войне против
Estonia, prepare for war. Well, everything is
Эстонии пр к войне готови Ну что всё
NATO is preparing for
НАТО готовится к
war. Oh well, nothing will happen, and
войне Да ладно ниче не буде уже и
Finland has entered  in on there we
Финляндия вошла в на есть мы
are doing no one there is
делаем никто не
no question that Russia will or will not
хо не вопрос что Россия нападёт или не
attack NATO there yes The question is that
нападёт там на НАТО да Вопрос в том что
Russia has already started a war Yes it attacked
Россия уже начала войну Да напала на
Ukraine and that’s all the question now  How will
Украину и всё сейчас вопрос Каким
Russia be slammed now we are waiting for
образом прихлопнут России сейчас ждём
Trump’s inauguration Yes, Trump should
инаугурации трампа Да Трамп должен
put Putin in place and give him 24 hours
поставить Путина вот да дать ему 24 часа
to make a decision on the withdrawal of troops if
на Принятие решения об отводе войск если
Trump doesn’t agree oh if this Putin doesn’t
Трамп не сог ой если этот Путин не
agree, then NATO will strike
соглашается да тогда НАТО нанесёт удар
at the territory of the Russian Federation, we are
по территории Российской Федерации у нас
already preparing in Estonia  Yes, Finland
в Эстонии уже готовят да Финляндия
is preparing a NATO base on the run, also
готовит базу НАТО бегом тоже в срочном
urgently. Everything here, well, we have
порядке Всё у нас ну у нас э проводятся
reservists. Yes, they called me up, so I went, too,
резервисты Да призвали вот я ходил тоже
uh, there is instruction on  civil
ээ идёт инструктаж по гражданской
defense We are also conducting full training in
обороне Полностью мы проводим также по
schools, that is, we are preparing what uh means in the
школам то есть готовимся что ээ значит в
first 2 days. E possible when a
первые 2 дня Э возможные вот когда
NATO attack on the territory of the
начнётся атака НАТО на территорию
Russian Federation will begin in the first 2 days
Российской Федерации первые 2 дня
since we are a border territory of
поскольку мы приграничная территория
NATO Russia and there may be
НАТО России да по нам могут быть
certain provocations from the
определённые провокации со стороны
Russian Federation. Yes  that’s why we are
Российской Федерации Да поэтому мы бомба
running bomb shelters And so on from this, that
убежища бегом И так дальше этом всё то
is, 2 days and Russia will not exist Well, as
есть 2 дня и России не будет Ну как
Russia will mean the center of
Россия будет имеется в виду центре
decision making will not be in
принятия решения не будет в
Russia, therefore there will be no war
России поэтому никакой войны не будет
Our all these bosses are  they understand there
Наши все эти начальники это понимают не
will be no war, the Kremlin will not be the Kremlin Look
войны не будет Кремль не Кремль Смотрите
at the Kremlin it will be inevitable
по Кремлю будет это уже неизбежно по
it will be struck at the Kremlin as if it were a
Кремлю будет нанесён он как по центру
blow to the decision-making center Yes, I don’t know Or it’s
принятия решений удар Да не знаю Или там
nuclear or ballistic Just maybe
ядерный или баллистический Просто может
some kind of American hazel tree there,
какой-то американский орешник там там
agave or something Yes That is, it  We already have
агав или что Да То есть это уже у нас
everything, we already have it, and on television we are being
уже всё у нас уже и по телевидению нас
prepared for this.
готовят к этому Да нас например
Yes, for example, we have sociological surveys. I was
опросы социологические вот я в Таллине
walking near the university in Tallinn yesterday and
возле университета гулял вчера и
they conducted it not not yesterday. It was the day before yesterday, and
проводили не не вчера Это позавчера было
they conducted a sociological survey. Yes.
да проводили социологический опрос Да
They ask how do you feel about the fact that America can launch a nuclear strike on Moscow next, and if not a nuclear strike? Yes, how do you feel about the fact that during America’s attack on Moscow on Moscow go to Europe, what is this cloud about the attack, yes So they look  They They are
удара да Так они же смотри они Они же
very simple, yes they are democratic They
очень просто да они демократически Они
evaluate yes, that is, for example, in Estonia, a
оценивают да то есть например в Эстонии
nuclear strike on Moscow has a negative
ядерный удар по Москве негативно
attitude. Because it seems like Near here
относится Потому что вроде как Рядом тут
Yes, but ballistic missile strikes
Да Во но удары баллистическими ракетами
there are a bark, everyone unanimously thinks  what
там гавка все единогласно считают что
is possible,
можно так
so in short they are tough on you there against
что короче вас там накручивают против
Russia in general Yes, yes, I’m helping to
России вообще жёстко Да да я я помогаю
cheat because well, we see that
накручивать потому что ну мы видим что
Russia attacked Ukraine and we understand
Россия напала на Украину и мы понимаем
that we can also be attacked, so we
что и на нас также может напасть поэтому
must strike first, you know the principle of the
надо бить первым знаете принцип
Tallinn gateway, what if a fight is
Таллинской подворотни что если драка
inevitable  Hit
неизбежна Бей
first, this is St. Petersburg, it’s not the same, it’s the St.
первым это это Питерская не та это
Petersburg people who stole it from us, so he took it from us,
питерцы у нас стянули так это ж он у нас
God forbid that nothing happens, God forbid
Дай Бог чтобы ничего не было Дай бо Дай
that in Moscow there
Бог чтобы по Москве
will be this then you can do everything  Well, this is
был вот это тогда всё вам может ну это
war Well, what
война Ну что
are
такое
stories And who do you work for, if it’s not a secret, a
истории А кем работаешь если не секрет
political analyst, a
политическим аналитиком
military-political
военно-политическим
analyst And who pays your salary,
аналитиком А кто тебе зарплату платит ми
if so figuratively Well, formally formally
если так образно Ну формально формально
English Yes formally look if
английская Да формально смотрите если
formally who pays me directly
формально кто непосредственно мне
yes What organization Yes it’s
выплачивают да Какая организация Да она
called the Institute for Eastern Studies
называется институт изучения Восточной
In Europe, there is such a think tank, and
Европы вот аналитический центр такой да
behind it stands the European Institute of
вот за ним стоит э Европейский институт
Think Tanks, not a European
аналитических центров не европейская
association of think tanks. Yes, but
ассоциация аналитических центров Да а
it is funded.
она финансируется
Well, you understand, yes,
Ну вы понимаете да
Britain. And that there are no Russian spies there
Британия И что там нету русских шпионов
like Buto. There are also  yes there is Well, of course,
как Буто Есть тоже да есть Ну конечно
look in our sphere, like, well, let’s
смотрите в нашей сфере типа ну что вот
give you credit
вам отдать должное
Yes, there are agents all over Europe and
Да агентуры своей вала по всей Европе и
for this in the USA, and so on. We
по этому по США и так дальше Вот у нас
had one colleague, he was also He there
была коллега один был он тоже Он там
wrote such analytical articles of the Armed Forces and
писал такие аналитические статьи ВС и
so on Yes  then they took him by the gills
так дальше Да потом его за жабры взяли
Because he was leaking information
Потому что он сливал информацию
like he and he
типа он а он
was in Russia about 15 years ago
короче был в России где-то 15 лет назад
then he was recruited in short they took him and
тогда был завербован короче взяли
fried him normally Well, you are probably
нормально прожарили Ну и Вы наверно там
under suspicion there that ideally you
под подозрением то что в идеале русским
should speak Russian  any moment Look, not
языком владеть в любой момен Смотри не
of course, but that’s what it is, there’s double
конечно да это же такое тут есть дабл
checking Yes, for example, We work in pairs,
чекинг Да например Мы работаем в парах
that is, so that the material
так то есть для того чтобы материал
we process, the decision on the
который мы обрабатываем решение об
report is made not by one person, but by two,
отчёте принимал не один человек а двое
that is, because it’s more
то есть потому что в сговор вступить
difficult for two people to conspire than for one  something to
двоим уже сложнее чем одному что-то
do so these are normal Well, let's say
сделать так вот это нормальные Ну скажем
If you work in this field Yes, it is
Если вы работаете в этой сфере Да тут
already clear that there are
уже понятно есть
certain, as it were in Russian,
определённые как бы как это по-русски
fuses
предохранители
Uh, as it were, well, restraining factors yes yes
Ээ как бы ну сдерживающие факторы да да
restraining factors Yes, of course and also for
сдерживающие факторы Да конечно и также
example  Russia bribes
например Россия делает подкуп и
officials and intelligence officers and analysts
чиновников и разведчиков и аналитиков
as well, yes
также да
Well, the work is interesting Well, the work I’m not complaining,
Ну работа интересна Ну работа Не жалуюсь
I saw it, let’s say The fact is that we
я я видел скажем Дело в том что у нас
have a section of our work,
как есть участок нашего нашей работы мы
for example, we analyze it, so I
например анализируем вот я
don’t write it down directly now, there are
непосредственно вы не записываете сейчас
n’t all sorts of bloggers And so  further
не есть всякие блогеры И так дальше
Yes, all
Да
sorts of things. I, my area of ​​responsibility
всякие Я в мою мою сферу ответственности
includes the analysis of the border
входит анализ приграничных
areas around Estonia, yes, that is, we
территорий вокруг Эстонии да то есть мы
analyze all the events, we look at
анализируем все события мы смотрим
the news of the Pskov region. Yes, we look at
новости Псковской области Да мы смотрим
uh where the movement of equipment looks at
ээ где перемещение техники смотрим
photos of all uh user here
фотографии всех ээ пользователь вот у
we have  a whole grid of people Yes, they are actually
нас есть целая сетка э людей Да они
browsing, they are actually subscribed to all the
просматривают реально подписаны на все
public pages, they are subscribed to active people, there
паблики подписаны на активных людей там
are photos of people there in the center there or a
фото ются люди там в центре там или
video, yes, a holiday is going on, a holiday is going on,
видео да проходит праздник проходит
we’re watching, yeah, there was a car in the back
праздник смотрим Ага сзади стояла там
with an interesting color scheme. What kind of
машина такой с интересной расцветкой Что
car is that? Well, let’s analyze it further
за машина так так Ну дальше анализируем
interesting, that is,
очень интересное есть то есть ээ
the movement of
перемещение
military personnel in the Pskov region, the
военного состава в Псковской области
placement of strategic objects
размещение стратегических объектов
that have priority targets for
которые имеют приоритетными целями для
destruction in the Pskov region,
поражения в Псковской области
the movement of senior
ээ передвижение высшего командного
military and civilian command personnel
состава командного военного и
in  Pskov region
гражданского состава в Псковской области
So there are people
Вот так есть люди
who say that
которые
it’s just like Gru directly
что это прямо как Гру прям тельно
management no no Gru is doing more
управление не нет Гру занимается более
interesting
интересными
things Well, I
вещами Ну как Я себе
imagine you have an idea from films,
представляю вас представление из фильмов
you don’t have an idea from films
не у вас из фильмов представление
Probably we know when we watch
Наверное мы знаете мы когда смотрим
films it’s funny to us, yes when
фильмы нам Аж смешно да когда
I  I like it so this is what I’m getting at Yes I
Мне нравится так вот к чему я веду Да я
have I’m doing a report with a partner only
имею Я делаю отчёт с напарником только
on the Pskov region and our department
по Псковской области да а наш отдел
does it on Eastern Europe and I
делает по Восточной Европе и мне
liked the title of the report it means about an
понравилось заголовок отчёта значит о
inevitable strike on Moscow that is ours  the
неминуемо удара по Москве то есть наш
analytical center,
аналитический центр
he said, made an expert decision, they
он скажем вынес экспертное решение
weighed the pros and cons, and that the blow
взвешивают все за и против да что удар
should have been dealt by the headline,
должен быть нанес заголовок отч меня
I just remember that, it’s
просто Вот я прям так запомнил
called peace, it’s not the absence of war,
называется мир это не отсутствие войны
it’s peace, it’s the absence of
Это мир - это отсутствие
Moscow I liked
Москвы Мне понравилось
BN Well, don’t you think that in Russia  5000
БН Ну а вы не думаете что в России 5000
nuclear missiles, where will they fly? Is it possible they
ядерных ракет куда они полетят Можно ли
won’t fly anywhere?
никуда не полетят всё
Look at everything after Ukraine through
смотрите после того как Украина через
NATO mercenaries. You understand that the
натовских наёмников Вы же понимаете там
Ukrainian army didn’t crush the hedgehog, Yes, the
же украинская армия еже не пере мололи
NATO army captured it.
Да там натовские армия Да захватила
Kursk region Yes, and Russia couldn’t answer in any way,
курскую область Да и Россия никак не
so everyone understood
смогла ответить поэтому всё все поняли
it’s like they
это ж как
’re probing the Kursk region Yes, for 4
прощупываются Курской область Да 4
months Russia can’t do anything,
месяца Россия ничего не может сделать
that is, they’re probing, I’m sorry for everything, Putin doesn’t have
всё то есть щупают прощу по всё нету у
your ruling elite so she’s
Путина ваша правящая верхушка так она
impotent, that’s all, well, you’ve taken over  but
импотент вот и всё не ну вы захватили но
you delayed it, well, you don’t mean
вы оттянули ну не вы имеете в виду вот
these guys. They pulled forces from other
эти ребята Они оттянули сил с других
directions and everything is going badly for them.
направлений и там у них всё плохо
Well, how bad everything is, no, everything is
получается Ну как всё плохо нет всё
bad. It’s in Russia Russia, look 3
плохо Это в России Россия смотрите 3
years ago it stood
года назад она стояла под Киевом Да её
near Kiev Yes, they dropped out of Kyiv from Kherson from Kharkov, now also from the Kursk region and the most important thing is that they showed that nothing can be done Now this Russia is being forced out of Syria, what do you think there, these are just bearded barmalei running around and Assad’s troops are expelling together with Russia No there Turkey will fulfill that Well, Turkey is the country of which military bloc Well, it’s not for the sake of this bloc that they do everything again Turkey is a NATO country where the American contingent of the Kurds is located Yes  the Turkish contingent, these guys
Да турецкий контингент вот эти ребята
who are now advancing from the North, everything is
которые сейчас с Севера наступает всё
clear, I was just looking at the
чётко я Я сегодня как раз смотрел про
Syrians today, it turns out there are Kurds
сирийцев там получается есть курды
who the Turks don’t like, but the
которые которых не любят турцы но их
Americans support them, it’s kind of a
поддерживают американцы там какой-то
wild mess, you’ll understand what’s
замес вообще дикий там поймёшь что
going on. Well, that is, NATO NATO in  Syria
происходит Ну то есть НАТО НАТО в Сирии
enters like America from the south and East Yes, the
входит типа Америка с юга и Востока Да
Kurds and Turkey with this is a hybrid,
курдами а Турция с это это гибрид
see the method of hybrid war like
смотрите метод гибридной войны как
the little green men Turkey America says
зелёные человечки Турция Америка говорит
we are not there, these are the Kurds and  some local
нас там нет это курды и какие-то местные
barmalei, that’s
бармалеи вот и
all Well, in short, we won’t have a fleet there soon.
всё Ну короче флота у нас там скоро не
Yes, soon you won’t have a fleet, and
будет Да скоро у вас флота не будет и
what’s more, there won’t be an air base,
мало того не будет авиационной базы
which was a transit point from
которая была перевалочный пунктом из
Africa, in fact, you’ll be thrown out of
Африки по сути вас выкинут этим из
Africa with this. We’ll see how it goes while everything is going on
Африки Посмотрим как будет пока всё ид
there, unknown, they were thrown out of the Kursk
там неизвестно выкинули из Курской
region, they were thrown out of Syria, they were thrown out of
области выкинули из Сирии выкинуть из
Africa Well, Trump will come, he said
Африки Ну вот Трамп придёт он же сказал
he’ll stop the conflict in a day, how will he
за сутки конфликт остановит как он его
stop it? Come on, an
остановит Да ну Путину
ultimatum to Putin Well, you’re real  do you believe that
Ультиматум Ну и ты реально веришь что
Putin will withdraw all troops from these
Путин выведет все войска с этих
territories so the question is look at the question is it not
территорий так вопрос смотрите вопрос не
whether Putin will withdraw the question that Biden
то выведет ли Путин вопрос что байден
said that he will stop in 24 hours if
сказал что остановит за 24 часа если
Putin Yes within 24 hours does not give the
Путин Да в течение 24 часов не не даёт
order to withdraw troops Yes Trump gives the
приказ о выводе войск Да Трамп даёт
order to strike Moscow here  and that's
приказ об ударе по Москве вот и
it Damn, I don't believe it Well, you
всё Блин ну я в это не верю Ну ты
agree, look at the military potential of the
согласен вое смотри военный потенциал
United States It's just not comparable to Russia, and the
США Просто не сравним с Россией а
military potential of the NATO bloc is not
военный потенциал блока НАТО вообще не
comparable to Russia at all Russia is just as
сравним с Россией Россия просто как
small  nut against a big
маленький орешек против большого
nut tree Well, we wouldn’t take North
орешника Ну мы бы не брали Северной
Korea’s missile so that everything would be fine with us
Кореи ракета чтобы у нас всё было хорошо
Well, I think so,
Ну ну я так думаю
but it seems to me that everything will stop because there
но мне кажется всё остановится так как
is just
есть просто вот на этой территории
some kind of zone in this demarcation territory, that is,
разграничения какая-то там зона то есть
Russia Russia will give the Kursk region to
Россия Россия отдаст курскую область
Ukraine  it
Украине
turns out it’s changing to Kharkov’s.
получается она меняется на харьковскую
Why did you decide that Ukraine
Каче че С чего вы решили что Украина
will change to Kharkov’s
будет менять на харьковскую
no? Yes, even if it gives it back. Well, Lord, it’s
нет Да даже если отдаст Ну Господи
better. It’s the other way around, in
лучше Это же наоборот вот на на самом
fact, those and now the same ones. And now the most  the
деле те а тепер самы А теперь самый
main question for
главный вопрос у
Russia is that
России что у
Russia has the right
России у России появилось право
to attract a foreign contingent of
привлекать иностранный контингент
Koreans like they are not Ukrainians,
корейцев типа они же не украи е если бы
if only Russia had attracted earlier, as if
если бы Россия раньше привлекала как что
someone would have said something to Russia,
что-то кто-то бы что-то сказал России а
well, it would have been considered like an intervention
ну это бы считалось как бы Интервенция
North Korea in the International conflict
Северной Кореи в Международный конфликт
and here it is all that someone at the UN would
а здесь она все что кто-то в ООН бы
complain to everyone North Korea and
пожаловался вообще всем Северная Корея и
so according to Sanmi, cooperation with North
так по санми сотрудничество Северной
Korea in the military sphere is prohibited with the
Корее в военной сфере запрещено со в
devil of the UN, which includes Russia,
бесом ООН в который входит России
so forget it in short  Damn, this is a completely different question. The fact is that Ukraine Yes, Ukraine now will not stop for what does it mean to stop, in short, this And what will you do, you don’t have the strength to capture Kyiv, really, yes Well, NATO through Ukraine with its hybrid forces there, you understand, it’s not the Ukrainians who are fighting, it’s the fighting Polish Mercenaries British Mercenaries American Mercenaries Colombian Yes professional military Yes you look at NATO in the Kursk region for some reason they don’t show you captured Ukrainians Yes and
поэтому забей короче блин тут вообще
In general, there are no prisoners, it’s true, because it
вообще пленных нету правда потому что
goes there Yes, because it went there
туда заходит Да потому что туда зашла
yesterday, yesterday, Kadaev showed a bunch of
вчера вчера кадаев показал плех
Ukrainians. I don’t know where they were from. That’s
украинцев Я не знаю откуда они были Вот
right. Yes. And why was there
именно Да А чтобы кого-то в Курской
no reason to take someone in the Kursk region?
области типа взять вообще не было почему
Because highly professional people came into the Kursk region?
Потому что в курскую область зашли
Yes  US Navy SEALs
высокопрофессиональные Да морские котики
Well, read it clearly from them. The fact is
США Вот они вычи у них чётко Дело в том
that you understand that without air
что вы же понимаете что без авиационной
support such an entry into the Kursk region would
поддержки такой заход в курскую область
most likely be impossible. Yes, that’s why
бы скорее всего Да вот поэтому
American aviation.
американская авиация Да ээ вот у нас как
Well, this can be public You can’t
типа ну это может публично Нельзя
tell it You’re definitely not
рассказывать Вы точно не
writing it down That’s for sure, I’ve read the same
записываете Вот точно вот читал тоже
type of analysis, it turns out over the Black
типа аналитику получается над чёрным
Sea Yes, this American reconnaissance officer is constantly
морем Да постоянно вот этот разведчик
cruising Yes, he
американский курсирует Да он
was read by radar and
радиолокационное считываются и
when NATO entered the Kursk region Yes,
когда НАТО заходила в курскую область Да
from a NATO base in the Mediterranean Sea yes,
с базы НАТО в Средиземном море да
uh, they took off f  -35 and they worked in the
ээ взлетели f-35 да и отработали по
Kursk region, yes They
Курской области да Они
destroyed these
уничтожили авиационными ударами эти
checkpoints in the Kursk
контрольно-пропускные пункты в Курской
region with air strikes, they destroyed places Wait, do our people
области уничтожили места Подожди а наши
know about this  Wait Yes, they destroyed the
об этом знают Подожди Да уничтожили
places where
места
personnel gathered Yes, why
скопления личного состава Да почему так
did it happen that they were able to pass the march in such a rush
получилось что смогли таким марш броском
True Well, they cleared it in advance and the most
Правда Ну зачистили заранее да и самое
interesting thing for us then is that
что интересное мы тогда дело в том что
we were already told at the institute that
нам тогда по институту уже сказали что
get ready now there will be an escalation
готовьтесь сейчас будет эскалация
possible A retaliatory strike on NATO countries
возможен Ответный удар по странам НАТО
Russian  Federation, we were all
Российской Федерации мы всё мы были уже
ready, but it seemed to show that
готовы но как бы показано было да что
Russia Russia could not
Россия Россия и не смогла ничего
answer America in any way. And your army is
ответить Америке А у вас армия она
professional or conscript in Estonia,
профессиональная или призывная в Эстонии
in Estonia it does not adhere to professional
в Эстонии не прина профессиональ
standards  we don’t have conscripts Well, you do
стандарты у нас нету призывных А ну вас
n’t have conscription there, no, that is,
у вас не призывают там не не то есть
NATO, see NATO, NATO standards Yes,
НАТО смотрите НАТО стандарты НАТО Да
only a professional
только профессиональная
army Well, Estonia, look, we have Estonia,
армия Ну Эстония смотрите у нас Эстония
we have a small army, in fact, yes, this is
маленькая у нас фактически армия Да это
no longer well, there are radars, some
не ну там радиолокационные некоторые
troops there in the Baltics, we have to
войска там в балтии мы чтобы пакости
Russia did dirty tricks like this, yes And they
России делали вот такого плана да А туда
go there, look, what’s the trick of the
же заходят смотрите заходят в чём фишка
modern NATO countries
воны стран НАТО современной
Yes, they enter NATO troops under the guise of
Да входят в войска НАТО под видом
local troops Yes, it seems like the ZSU enters,
местных войск Да вроде как входит зсу
then they show the commander of the ZSU,
потом показывают командующий зсу
we tell  they took it, yes Or they show
рассказывают мы взяли да Или показывают
someone in the court, they bring these
какого-то в суджу завозят этих
Ukrainian military already Yes, they
украинских уже военных Да они там
show there, we captured everything here, that is, they
показывают мы тут захватили всё то есть
don’t show how the assaults True, they
не показывают как штурмы Правда они
carry out not only in NATO there are a lot of
проводят не тем более в НАТО много
Russian-speaking military, in principle, it’s possible
русскоязычных военных в принципе можно
too But Estonia has claims to
тоже А вот у Эстонии есть претензии к
Russian territorial
России территориальные
there, well, well, the fact is that look, part of the
там ну ну Дело в том что смотрите часть
Pskov region, yes, these are historical
Псковской области да это исторические
Estonian
эстонские
territories, part of the Leningrad region,
территории часть Ленинградской области -
these are historical Finnish territories and
это исторические финские территории и
Swedish ones, and we support the fraternal Finnish people,
шведские и мы Братский финский народ
yes  plus
поддерживаем да плюс
Yes Karelia and here is the city of Vyborg, you
Да Карелия и вот город Выборг вы же
know yes Stalin during the attack on
знаете да Сталин во время нападения на
Finland in 1939 yes he took away
Финляндию в три девятом году да отобрал
part of the territory of
часть территории
Finland So yes, well, he is there and there too The
Финляндии Так что да ну он там да и там
fact is that we Well, you know,
Дело в том что мы Ну вы же знаете
Estonians and Finns are peoples
эстонцы и фины - это народы
Finno-Ugric language group Do you
финно-угорской языковой группы А вы
understand each other yes yes yes we
понимаете друг друга да да да мы
understand let’s say so we understand How you and the
понимаем скажем так мы понимаем Как вы и
Ukrainians skra like this Ilu with
украинцы скра вот так Илу
your mouth Who is there Co and so Dasha Here and now
ртом Кто там Ко и так Даше Вот и сейчас
Yes we  We clearly raise the issue of protecting the
Да мы чётко поднимаем вопрос о защите
Finno-
фино
Ugric peoples because they are
угорской народов потому что они
oppressed in the Russian Federation. Yes, the
притесняют в Российской Федерации Да
fact is that the Russian Federation there
дело в том что там Российская Федерация
should ideally be divided into the
в идеале должна быть разделена на
territory inhabited by the Finno-Ugric
территории проживания фино угорских
peoples, Jurassic peoples and others, there is a
народов юрских народов и других есть
confederation of Turkic peoples, there is
конфедерация из тюркских народов есть
such a political project Look, it
такой проект политический Посмотрите
’s called the Great  Turan Yes Great
называется Великий Туран Да Великий
Turan That is, how yes, that is, Russia is
Туран То есть как да то есть Россия
prora different concepts The thing is
прора разные концепции Есть дело в том
that the question is that how should
что вопрос в том что как бы Какой должна
Russia be against Putin on  in the West there
быть Россия против Путина на западе тут
are several opinions, some believe
есть несколько мнений некоторые считают
that it is necessary to bring there something like Gorbach,
что нужно привести там вроде как Горбач
who will do perestroika and will
который Сделает перестройку да и будет
do it like in the Soviet
деть как в Советском
Union, but the majority, the majority and the
Союзе но большинство большинство и
director of our analytical center
директор нашего аналитического центра
also lobby for this opinion that
тоже лоббирует это мнение что
replacing,
смена
say, the Russian Tsar with a good one will
скажем российского царя на хорошего Да
not lead to anything  because
ни к чему не приведёт потому что всё
anyway, after him some bad guy will come.
равно после него придёт какой-то плохой
Yes, if we take the Soviet Union.
Да вот если мы возьмём Советский Союз Да
Well, after Stalin there was Khrushchev. Yes, the
ну после Сталина был Хрущёв Да что
troops in Prague
войска в Прагу
and in Budapest they crushed  An uprising Well, there
Да в Будапеште давили Восстание то Ну
was some kind of Thaw there, what a
какая-то Оттепель была же там какая
Thaw Yes, and he knocked there and the Cuban missile
Оттепель Да и он там стучал и Карибский
crisis was also under Khrushchev.
кризис это тоже при хрущёве Да
Yes, Brezhnev Brezhnev troops in Afghanistan
вот Брежнев Брежнев войска в Афганистан
VL, that is, there are no good ones, that is, while
ВЛ то есть нету хороших да то есть пока
this territory will be so big Yes,
эта территория будет такой большой Да
it will be difficult  to imperial greatness and the
она будет тя готе к имперскому величию и
seizure of new territories, that
захвату новых территорий то
is, very clearly.
есть очень чётко Да
Yes, this Russian Empire was destroyed
что вот эту Российскую империю развалили
in 1917, taken away from it there  Finland
в 1917 году отобрал от неё там Финляндию
Latvia Lithuania Estonia Ukraine Poland And
Латвию Литву Эстонию Украину Польшу И
so on Yes, then Lenin and steel
так дальше Да потом Ленин со стальным
took back a little of these territories
немножко захватили назад этих территорий
In the ninety-first year, the so-
В девяносто первом году прошёл так
called second stage of the collapse of the
называемый второй этап распада
Russian Empire took place, that is, the Soviet
Российской Империи то есть Советский
Union was divided into 15 independent countries,
Союз расчленили на 15 стран независимых
depriving Russia of the mobilization
лишив э Россию мобилизационного
potential of scientific and technical
потенциала научно-технического
potential and  resource potential, yes, that
потенциала и ресурсного потенциала да то
is,
есть
minerals And so on, yes, that
полезные ископаемые И так дальше да то
is, and as we see now Russia is not
есть и как мы видим сейчас Россия не в
able  to carry out some large-scale
состоянии проводить какие-то масштабные
military operations like those carried out by the
такие военные операции как проводил
Soviet Union and now the final
Советский Союз и теперь окончательный
third stage of the collapse of the Russian Empire,
третий этап распада Российской Империи
and that is, the disintegration of the Russian Federation
да то есть распад Российской Федерации
into independent states, you see how
на независимые государства вы видите как
technically I think you can’t help but
технично Я думаю вы это не можете не
mark this as
помечать как
technically,
технично в Россию последними годами
representatives of the non-Russian have brought manure into Russia in recent years
навоз представители нерусского мусуль
Muslim population Yes, bearers of other
нского населения Да носители других
cultures different from Russia Like Ramzan
культур отличных от России Как Рамзан
Kadyrov now, in fact,
Кадыров сейчас фактически
resist
противостаньте
all these barmalei who are
все вот эти бармалеи которые
pressing the Siege, where will they go now
жмут Осада куда они сейчас денутся
Assad's, these are all not who are
Асадов ские вот эти все нет которые
against the Siege Now where will they
против Осада Сейчас куда они денутся
go when the Siege is expelled? Well, I hope that our barmalei will run to them, we have these barmalei
к ним побегут у нас же этих бармалеев
of ours
своих
x State and there they are right
х Государство и там они вот как раз
now when the Doge of Syria Yes, when the Doge of
сейчас когда дож Сирию Да когда дож
Syria with Assad yes  this whole public is being
Сирию с асадом да всю эту публику пере
reoriented towards the Caucasus, the Caucasus specifically
ориентируют на Кавказ Кавказ конкретно
Chechnya Ingushetia Dagestan Let it be the point
Чечня Ингушетия Дагестан Да будет точкой
that and how is it possible to push
которая а а как это чез Турцию протащить
this through Turkey  Turkey should participate
этоже это должна Турция участвовать
Turkey and Turkey isn’t participating in Syria
Турция а Турция в Сирии не участвует
isn’t it Why does it need to squeeze the Caucasus further
разве не А зачем ей надо Кавказ ещё
Because because Turkey Yes
обжимать Потому что потому что Турция Да
wants to unite the influence of all the
хохочет объединить влияние всех
Islamic post-Soviet republics with
исламских постсоветских республик с
Azerbaijan already like that’s all with Here’s my
Азербайджаном уже типа всё с Вот вот моё
opinion to really hold a referendum there
мнение реально провести референдум там
Chechnya Dagestan Ingushetia what  people will decide to
Чечня Дагестан Ингушетия что люди решат
start stop PP Everything, forget about any
пуска стоп ПП Всё забудь никаких
referendums, it was already necessary in the
референдумов уже это надо было в
nineties to let them go into independence
девяностых отпускать их в независимость
Now this is  will no longer be that is,
Сейчас такого уже не будет то есть
now
сейчас
uh Chechnya Ingushetia Dagestan will be
ээ Чечня Ингушетия Дагестан будут
used as uh let’s say an element of
использоваться как ээ скажем элемент
destabilization of the Russian Federation
дестабилизации Российской Федерации как
right now it’s beneficial for you Yes, run them
раз вам сейчас вам выгодно Да бегом их
uh make them uh other countries Yes, but
ээ сделать их ээ другими странами Да а
isolate yourself from them with visa regimes
отгородиться от них визовым режимами
so that they don’t squeeze it’s not all too late too
чтобы они не прижали не не всё поздно
late  late it should have been done
поздно поздно это надо было могли делать
in the nineties Yes now yes now there is
в девяностых Да сейчас да сейчас
tension The fact is that uh Chechnya
напряжение Дело в том что ээ Чечня
Dagestan and Ingushetia Yes this is a large
Дагестан и Ингушетия Да это большая
concentration of young active uh  evil
концентрация молодых активных ээ злых
men really look uh If we
мужчин правда вот посмотрите э Если мы
look like in the Russian Federation uh
смотрим как в Российской Федерации ээ
When somewhere in everyday or street
Когда где-то в бытовых или уличных
issues Caucasians
каких-то вопросах сталкиваются кавказцы
and Russians collide Yes the Russians immediately herd the
и русские Да русские сразу пасут
Caucasian he is always clear tough Yes he is
кавказец он всегда чёткий жёсткий Да он
Russian Well that’s how you are so not sure Well
русский Ну вот как вы так не уверено Ну
Yes, they’re just originally athletes,
да они просто они изначально спортсмены
it’s like they’re constantly doing it, that’s my
они как бы они постоянно они вот моё
opinion, they’re straight tough nationalists, that’s
мнение они прям националисты жёсткие
right, look, they’re boiling in their own
правильно смотри они в своём варятся
cauldron, all
котле все вот
these, all 20  years of Putin's rule What
эти все 20 лет правления Путина Что
did the Caucasus do, it trained new
делал Кавказ он готовил новых
fighters everything And moreover, when under
бойцов всё И больше того когда при
Yeltsin, yes When the first Chechen second was there, the
ельцине да Когда была там первая
Caucasians mostly lived in the Caucasus in
кавказцы в основном жили на Кавказе в
Russian cities. There were a limited
русских городах их было Ну ограниченное
number of them, as from the end of the Sovka there were
количество как с конца Совка были там
criminal elements there, some kind of gangs
криминальные элементы какие-то банды
athletes But the vast majority of them were not there
спортсмены Но их не было подавляющее
now I think you don’t need to
большинство сейчас я думаю вы не надо
tell you that in schools and
вам рассказывать да что уже и в школах и
on the streets and in taxis my daughter is studying in the
на улицах и в такси дочка учится в
first grade with not 30 of them.
первом классе у не 30 человек из них Вот
Guys, since the
ребята сль
thirteenth year of its construction, it was built by
тринадцатого года постройки его строили
Armenians, 20 percent of Armenians are not here,
армяне здесь процентов 20 армян нет тут
as if there are no
как бы нету каких-то конфликтов
interethnic conflicts, so look correctly in
межнациональных так правильно смотри в
the Soviet Union, there
Советском в Советском Союзе тоже же не
was no Soviet Union either.
было Советский Союз Дружба народов была
the truth exploded Well, yes, I have an aunt from Kazakhstan,
правда Ну да у меня тётка из Казахстана
and now it will be Yes, now it will be
е вот-вот а теперь будет Да теперь будет
Look, there are no Russian people left in Chechnya
Смотри в Чечне не осталось русских людей
not left
не осталось
Chechnya seems to have lost in Chechnya 95%
Чечня вроде проиграла в Чечне 95%
of the population are Chechens Russians 15% here in
населени это чеченцы русских 15% вот в
Ingushetia 98% Ingush and so on in
Ингушетии 98% ингушей и так дальше в
the Republic of Sakha Under the Soviet Union there
Республике Саха При Советском Союзе
were less than
было менее
50% of Sakha now there are already 80% of them, that is, the
50% Саха сейчас их уже 80% да то есть
Russians are being forced out of all these republics
русских вытесняют из всех этих республик
and
и больше
Moreover, I don’t have a friend from Yakutia,
того не у меня есть приятель из Якутии
this is not there, well, I’ll honestly tell you
там этого нету ну я те честно скажу
what’s there in  Yakutia
что-что там в Якутии вот этого никакого
doesn’t have any of this. Come on, my friend, I don’t know about eating or
нету Прити меня приятель про есть не
eating, I don’t know, but the Russian population
есть я не знаю но население русская
is leaving Yakutia, that’s all, not
уезжает из Якутии вот и всё так вот не
because they are oppressed there, it’s just the
из-за того что там притесняют просто там
climate there. Maybe, yes, well, the point is that let’s
климат Может быть да ну Суть в том что
say the conditions for Ruso are  are improving
скажем условия для Русо они улучшаются с
every year and now they are approaching the
каждым годом и сейчас они подходят к
ideal because the
идеальном потому что государственная
Russian state machine is weaker than ever and
машина России как никогда
T is dying in Ukraine in Syria and
слаба сиво Т умирает в Украине в Сирии и
in others Yes, it is tied up there Therefore,
в других Да он завязан там Поэтому
let’s say the ethno Rimini gang  rise And
скажем этно Римини банды поднимаются А
you understand that there is Kadyrov Yes, it’s
вы же понимаете что э там Кадыров Да это
not just Chechens living in different cities,
не просто чеченцы в разных городах живут
Yes, Chechens in cities are a clearly
Да чеченцы в городах это чётко
structured Mafia that is
структурированная Мафия которая
subordinate to the Chechen in the region, there is a
подчиняется ээ чеченцу в области есть
lookout, there is, in short, and so on And
смотрящий есть короче и так дальше Да и
above them Kadyrov is also Azerbaijanis,
над ними Кадыров также азербайджанцы
Tajiks, that’s all  yes, these ethnic ones are
таджики ту все все да этнические эти
even more than that, I’ll surprise you, we
даже больше того я вас Удивлю мы
analyzed the Slavic uh these
анализировали славянские э-э эти
diasporas in the Russian Federation, even
диаспоры в Российской Федерации даже
among Ukrainians there are even though the majority
среди украинцев есть хотя большинство
Ukrainians There they are so uh sort of
украинцев Там они так Ээ как бы
dissolved and with the
растворены да с
assimilation of Ukrainians there are very
ассимилировать украинцев есть очень
clear uh diasporas especially the
чёткие ээ диаспоры особенно
Greek Catholic diaspora they
греко-католическая диаспора они
are on the floor of this semi-lenal regime they
находятся на полу этом полулен режиме
have
имеют
positions they promote their people to
должности продвигают своих людей по
different positions they seem to support
разных должностях вроде как поддерживают
Russia but they kind of do harm very much
Россию но как бы так вредят очень сильно
harm the rumors  I didn’t even know about the diaspora, their
вредят слы даже не знал не диаспоры их
appearance, they have clashes here, there are
вид у них тут стычки происходят там
Tajiks with Daga back and forth, that’s right
таджики с Дага там туда-сюда это да а
Ukrainians They don’t answer at all,
украинцы Они вообще не отве
don’t pay attention to them When you
на них не обращаете внимания Когда вы
see a Chechen, a Caucasian or a Tajik,
видите чеченца там кавказца или таджика
you immediately visually understand yes And so
вы сразу о визуально понимаете да А так
you think that it’s
вы думаете что это
Russian Well, we have problems with them Well, as
русский Ну у нас проблем с ними Ну как
you saw, how they
вы видели как там то Дашу дугину
blew up Dasha Dugin and whatnot  - yes, some how
взорвали то ещё что-то да какие-то как
it’s all done,
это всё делается
of course Well, most likely Yes, people who
конечно Ну скорее всего Да люди которые
have once been somewhere in Ukraine or
где-то когда-то побывали в Украине либо
Ukrainians themselves Yes, most likely Well,
сами украинцы Да так скоре всего Ну всё
anyway, the FSC finds them It’s not  it’s so
равно их фски находит Это же не так
simple Now there’s a camera everywhere Moscow It’s
просто Сейчас везде камера Москва Она
all in full view here at all, no, it’s the
вся как на ладони здесь вообще не не это
same thing, you can’t die, well, you can’t
самое не подохнуть та Ну что-то не
die on the Tajiks in the crocus. So
продохнуть на таджики в крокусе Так
cool, well, the FSB agents have already overlooked
прикольно ну это уже фсбшники проглядели
that, but I don’t mean these domestic
вот не я имею в виду вот эти бытовые
crimes there, too Well  they were identified
преступления там ещё Ну их же вычислили
anyway, these Tajiks, you
всё равно этих таджиков вы вы же
understand that among the FSB employees there are a
понимаете что среди работников ФСБ
huge number of also representatives of
огромное количество тоже представителей
diasporas, including the Ukrainian
диаспор в том числе украинской
diaspora. Well, as for  there are
диаспоры Ну что касается среднеазиатских
practically no Central Asian and Caucasian people there, just
и кавказских там Практически нет как раз
look at the releases of the
кавказских посмотри Посмотрите выпуски
FSB Academy over the past 20
академии ФСБ за последние 20
years. Well, I know that in Moscow there are just Caucasians from the Ministry of Internal Affairs. Well,
лет Ну я знаю что Москве из МВД просто
roughly
кавказцев Ну выталкивают грубо
speaking, they don’t even hire a person, a person
говоря даже не берут на работу человек
comes with a higher education
приходит у него высшее образование там
here and there, his last name is there  Mikoyan
туда-сюда у него фамилия там Микоян
bro, goodbye,
братан до свидания
this is Nazism,
так это нацизм
well, this is not Nazism, this is
ну это не нацизм это
just a warning of Nazism, well,
просто это предупреждение нацизма ну
wait, like a Nazi if a person is a citizen  In the
подожди как наци если человек гражданин
Russian Federation, he has all the rights,
Российской Федерации он имеет все права
he is not hired for his last name, nor Kayan. It’s like in the
его за фамилию ни Каян не взя Это как в
Soviet
Советском
Union, Russians were only allowed to pass, this is
Союзе русских только пропускали это
Nazism, but not all Ukrainians allowed a
нацизм ну да не всех пропуска Украин
person to pass because of his Nationality,
человека за его Национальность не взяли
this is Nazism.
на работу это нацизм
Well, I don’t
Ну я так не
think so, they just don’t go there to work
считаю просто они идут туда не работать
they are starting to do weird things there Why is the problem
они начинают там чудить Почему проблема
that these bodies are Corum They are
в том что эти органы они Корум Они
corrupt how many of these
коррумпированные сколько у вас там этих
generals have you detained there who
генералов задержали которые взятки
took bribes Well there in
брали Ну там в
Ponya Okay let’s run otherwise it’s too late
Поня Хорошо давай побегу а то уже поздно
go to bed today Come on, you're wearing
надо ложиться спать сегодня Давай ты
something in a hat, it's cold there in Estonia, this is the
что-то в шапке там холодно в эстони это
style so that we don't
стиль такой ну чтобы причёску мы не
see the hairstyle okay good luck
видели ладно удачи
Yes,
Да вот
Povaliy subscribe comment everyone who wants
Повалий подписка комент все кто хочет
another blow to Moscow like subscribe
прочий удар по Москве лайк подписка
comment write to th Telegram right now axis
комент пись на й Telegram прям зараз ось
VN
ВН
apok tse  very and very politely YouTube took
апок це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня
us through the ODS carg to your ban and the
нас через карг ОРВ в твый бан и дуже
video is not very rich  I show people constantly not
багато видео не показую людям вчасно не
showing information about streams so
показуе информация про стримы тому для
that we Mali operational link
того щоб мы Мали оперативный звязок
write directly immediately and Popik there in
пишите прямо зараз а Попик там в
telegram okrim video also the same Tsikava and
телеграми окрим видео ще теж е цикава и
Korisna information and we are guilty of you
корисна информация и мы повинни з вами
trimati postiy operational link
тримати постийний оперативный звязок
independantly in that chi show you the process
незалежно в того чи покаже вам про це
YouTube Glory to Ukraine
YouTube Слава украини
letter
пись а